seniormbp.com 2016-02-21

# Verio Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy for Customer and Visitor Information

* * *

**As of May 26, 2015, _Endurance International Group_ acquired the non-Cloud(n) retail Verio business and consenting viaVerio Channel Partners and assumed the privacy policy for these accounts. If you are a non-Cloud(n) retail Verio customer or a viaVerio Channel Partner, look for more information in your inbox over the next few months. If you have any questions, please email us at [transition@verio-inc.com](mailto:transition@verio-inc.com).**

Verio, a business unit of NTT America, Inc.  
Effective: April 1, 2015

As of April 1, 2015, Verio Inc. has merged with its parent company, NTT America, Inc. The following Privacy Policy applies to all “Verio” products and services.

We, Verio, a business unit of NTT America, Inc., (“Verio”), value the business of our customers and are committed to protecting any data that we collect regarding our customers. By using Verio’s websites and/or purchasing Verio’s products and services (the “Services”), you (either a visitor to a Verio corporate website or a Customer) agree to the use of the data that we collect in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time, at Verio’s sole discretion. Verio will provide you a notice of material changes to this Privacy Policy (e.g., material changes to the way Verio uses or discloses your Personal Information) by disclosing this amendment on its homepage and providing electronic notice of such changes on your Control Panel or BackRoom or to the email address we have on file. Your continued use of this website or the Services following your receipt of notice of material changes constitutes your agreement with any changes or modifications that Verio may make. 

This Privacy Policy applies only to Verio’s treatment of data collected online, and does not apply to any offline data collection practices or to the data collection practices of any third parties, Verio customers, or any entities affiliated with Verio. 

Verio collects two types of information: Personally Identifiable Information (such as your name and e-mail address) (“PII” and “Personal Information”) and Non-Personally Identifiable Information (such as information that cannot be used to identify you individually) (“Non-Identifiable Information”). 

  1. **Non-Identifiable Information**

Verio may collect public or Non-Identifiable Information such as your usage information contained in “cookies” in order to: optimize the functionality of our website, personalize your experience on our website, perform system maintenance, and perform data analysis (such as broad general demographic analytics). You may choose to disable cookies, but that may decrease the functionality of Verio’s website. 

  2. **Personal Information**

In order to provide you with Services, Verio may collect a variety of Personal Information. This information may include, but not be limited to: your name, your contact information (including e-mail address, phone number, and mailing address), your domain name(s), and financial information such as your credit card. During the provision of Services, Verio may also develop other Personal Information in your account such as your transaction history. All Personal Information collected through this website will be collected using a secure server and will be stored in accordance with Verio’s Information Security Policy.

    1. **Use and Protection of Personal Information:**  
Generally, Personal Information is used for billing purposes and in order to provision and provide the Services. Verio may also use this information in order to assess our customers’ needs and provide support. Verio collects this information in accordance with its Information Security Policy, which includes physical, electronic, and managerial safeguards to protect your Personal Information. In addition, Verio may contact our customers with voluntary materials, such as system usage information, newsletters, and other mailings or contacts containing promotions or other marketing materials for Verio or its Channel Partners ([www.viaverio.com](http://www.viaverio.com/)), selected vendors, and Affiliates. Any customer who receives these mailings or calls may Opt-Out from these voluntary communications at any time. Verio does not sell or otherwise transfer any Personal Information to third parties for the purposes of marketing communications, but may occasionally contact you on behalf of its Channel Partners, selected vendors, and Affiliates.

Verio’s Corporate Websites, defined as websites owned or under the control of Verio Inc. (either by itself or with another entity), use cookies to collect information about website visitors’ activities, and our servers use a mechanism to collect certain information from your browser during the ordering process. Verio uses this information to (1) recognize returning customers when they sign in, (2) understand how customers arrived at the websites, so Verio can provide relevant content and information, (3) remember customers’ preferences, (4) protect against fraud, (5) provision any services ordered, and (6) provide information for analytics about the websites, such as total number of visitors and page views. You can choose to reject cookies at any time by changing your browser settings, but you should be aware that by blocking cookies, you will limit Verio’s ability to provide you with services you request. If you choose to order services from Verio, Verio’s Corporate Websites do not allow customers to block the collection of information that is necessary to provide you services and protect against fraud.

Verio does not allow third parties to collect personal information directly from users of its Corporate Websites. Verio provides customer support through a website owned by a third party. This website uses session cookies in order to determine whether visitors to the website are returning customers, but these cookies disappear from visitors’ browsers when the browser is closed. Verio does share de-identified information with third parties for purposes of conducting analytics for Verio. Please review the onward transfer section for more information about how Customer information is shared with third parties. Verio retains ownership of the data it shares and does not permit the third parties to use the data for other purposes.

    2. **Onward Transfer of Personal Information:**  
During the provision of Services, Verio may release Personal Information to third parties as necessary to the purposes described above. Third party recipients of Personal Information may include Verio’s Third-Party Providers, vendors, credit card processing companies, and your financial institution, as applicable. Verio only provides this information to third parties to the extent required to fulfill our obligations to you. More information about Verio’s Third-Party Providers can be found in the Terms and Conditions for your Services, which can be found by logging into your Control Panel or BackRoom. Verio provides this information in accordance with Verio’s Information Security Policy and all recipients are required to agree in writing to comply with Verio’s Information Security Policy with regards to their own treatment of the Personal Information. 

While Verio does not sell its customer lists, in the case of a merger or sale of Verio’s business or a substantial portion of Verio’s assets, customers’ Personal Information will likely be part of the assets transferred. In this event, Verio will attempt to notify impacted customers, using their contact information on file, that their Personal Information has been transferred.

    3. **Access and Accuracy:**  
You may access, review, and correct or update your information by logging into your Control Panel or Back Room. If you have any problems logging in, please contact Verio’s Customer Care team at <http://support.verio.com/contact/technical.cfm>. In order to access and review your information, you may be required to provide additional information in order to confirm your identity. If you are not a Verio Customer or you have provided your information for Opt-Out purposes and you would like to correct or update your information, you may enter in your updated Opt-Out information on our Opt-Out page or you may contact us using the contact information below. You may use these methods to delete information as well, but Verio may retain Personal Information provided in order to provide the Services or ensure that your Opt-Out preferences are retained. Deletion in these cases may cause Service termination or removal from our Opt-Out lists.

    4. **Retention:**  
Verio retains this Personal Information only as long as necessary to provide Services or as required or permitted by law. Verio will dispose of any Personal Information in accordance with its Information Security Policy.

  3. **Communications Preferences**

Verio may contact our customers with voluntary materials, such as system usage information, newsletters, and other mailings or contacts containing promotions or other marketing materials for Verio or its Partners and Affiliates. Any customer who receives these mailings or calls may Opt-Out from these voluntary communications at any time. 

It is important to note, however, that customers may not Opt-Out from transactional or required communications, including but not limited to: purchase confirmations, billing notifications, important system updates, and communications to provide service or support. 

To control your communications preferences, please go to Verio’s Opt-Out page, located here: www.verio.com/about/legal/privacy/solicitation/. 

If you are not a Verio customer and Verio received your information from a third party for the purposes of marketing communications and you wish to Opt-Out from future non-transactional communications, Verio will retain your information on its global Opt-Out list indefinitely. In order to Opt-Out, please go to Verio’s Opt-Out page, located here: www.verio.com/about/legal/privacy/solicitation/. If you have previously Opted Out and need to update your information, please enter your new information on the Opt-Out page. 

  4. **Customer Websites and Third-Party Websites**

Verio provides hosting services, both directly to retail customers and through Resellers & Channel Partners. This Privacy Policy only applies to information submitted directly to Verio. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, nor does Verio provide any guarantee for, any data or information submitted to any other person or entity, including any person or entity that may be a customer, directly or indirectly, of Verio. Verio does not exercise authority or control over its customers, nor does it censor or monitor its customers’ sites, and you should carefully assess any such website prior to submitting data or information to them. 

Verio’s websites may also contain links to external sites and co-branded sites (such as a site offered by a third party that may also include Verio’s logo and provide discounted services to Verio customers), which may be operated by a third-party and will have its own privacy policy. When you click on these links, you will be subject to the third-party’s privacy policy and its other policies, and these policies may be different from Verio’s own policies. Verio cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of these third-party websites, their collection practices, and their content. 

  5. **Required Disclosure**

Verio will disclose any information about you upon a valid request as we, in our sole discretion, believe is necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and any legal process (including but not limited to, subpoenas, warrants, and court orders). Verio may also disclose any information about you as necessary, in Verio’s sole discretion, to protect the safety of the public or any person, protect your property or rights, protect the property and rights of any third party, bring legal action against someone who may be causing harm or interfering with the rights or property of Verio, Verio’s customers, or others, or to stop any activity that is in violation of Verio’s Acceptable Use Policy. 

Verio will not, except for reasons stated below, disclose to third parties the contents of any electronic mail or other electronic communications that Verio stores or transmits for its customers. The circumstances under which Verio will disclose such electronic customer communications are when: 

    1. it is necessary in order to provide service to the customer; 
    2. it is necessary to protect the legitimate interests of Verio and its customers; 
    3. it is necessary to cooperate with interception orders, warrants, or other legal process; or
    4. it is necessary to provide to a law enforcement agency when the contents are inadvertently obtained by Verio and appear to pertain to the commission of a crime.

Verio disclaims any intention to censor, edit or engage in ongoing review or surveillance of communications stored on or transmitted through its facilities by customers or others. Verio may, however, review, delete, or block access to communications that may harm Verio, its customers or third parties. The grounds on which Verio may take such action include, but are not limited to, actual or potential violations of Verio’s Acceptable Use Policy or its Global Terms and Conditions. 

  6. **Contact Us**

Questions, comments, or complaints regarding Privacy Policy and data collection and processing practices can be mailed or emailed to: 

> VERIO, a business unit of NTT America, Inc.  
>  Attention: Legal Department  
>  5050 Conference Way North  
>  Boca Raton, FL 33431  
>  Opt-Out
